<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lewis Nyman</title>
    <description>Lewis Nyman's personal thinking spot.</description>
    <link>http://lewisnyman.co.uk</link>
    <atom:link href="http://lewisnyman.co.uk/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Ampersand 2015</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I attended Ampersand Conference in Brighton. As it was just down the road it seemed like a no brainer, but it blew me away. I feel certain it was my favourite conference of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to care about typography, a lot. I used to be so passionate about it. In recent years, I&amp;#39;d forgotten to care about it. As I moved toward high level design thinking and UX, component based design, and pattern libraries. It&amp;#39;s easy to forget about the little details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This conference was all about the little details. The scope was so focused that each talk was a deep dive into the obsessions of the speaker. Each one was a fascinating tale. Watching every speaker care so much reminded me what I used to care about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The attendees were also brilliant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Indra Kupferschmid&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Down with Web Typography&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indra is a German Professor and Typographer. She showed us how to apply classic typography principles to the web, how these rules haven&amp;#39;t changed in many years. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a great talk for beginners and a nice reminder for experienced designers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Marcin Wichary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;To Hell for Type&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marcin is a designer and developer working for Medium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marcin captivated the entire audience talking about all the terrible sins he has committed all in the name of  a great reading and writing experience on Medium.com. My favourite example was that he &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@mwichary/fixing-a-chrome-dictionary-issue-bbd7c5314f01#.o8qmnmgcz&quot;&gt;submitted bug fix to Chromium&lt;/a&gt; to prevent smart quotes being flagged as mis-spellings. Other great stories are [The curious case of the disappearing &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/medium-eng/the-curious-case-of-disappearing-polish-s-fa398313d4df#.x6ma5f8lx&quot;&gt;Polish S&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@mwichary/system-shock-6b1dc6d6596f#.5iamh16hg&quot;&gt;System Shock: a story of a 25-year-old font coming back with a vengeance.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Jen Simmons&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://speakerdeck.com/jensimmons/modern-layouts-getting-out-of-our-ruts-40-mins&quot;&gt;Modern Layouts: Getting out of our ruts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jen talked about her impatience with the done-and-done three column layout we see on almost every site. She presented her research into experimental magazine article layouts. This lead her to show us what we can do to push the boundaries of design using modern web standards. It was a great case for art direction on the web and I liked how she covered how to handle this in a CMS, because that&amp;#39;s always an issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Nick Sherman&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The future of responsive typography&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nick is on the board of directors for the Type Directors Club, as well as being the co-founder of the excellent &lt;a href=&quot;http://fontsinuse.com&quot;&gt;Fonts In Use.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nick described the way we select typefaces and weights as being stuck in the past. It&amp;#39;s same way type has been selected and used since movable type was invented. What if there was another way to use type, that&amp;#39;s closer to how we manipulate HTML with CSS?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nick laid out his ideas of a system that can generate fonts algorithmically. Instead of loading individual font files for each weight or style, you&amp;#39;d load just one, and the browser can use the information to manipulate the display of the type.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was mind-explodey stuff. It was great to see the thoughts of someone so heavily involved in digital type.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Bruno Maag&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Designing typefaces for screens&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bruno is a Swiss type designer from the type agency &lt;a href=&quot;https://daltonmaag.com&quot;&gt;Dalton Maag.&lt;/a&gt; He presented a fascinating case study on creating the &lt;a href=&quot;http://typedetail.com/bookerly.html&quot;&gt;Bookerly font&lt;/a&gt; for Amazon Kindle. It&amp;#39;s interesting to see how much work and detail goes into designing a typeface. The special considerations that went into e-ink screens was really interesting. I don&amp;#39;t know how someone could design a typeface for so many languages and contexts without going crazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Lu Yu&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://speakerdeck.com/lugotype/chinese-design-for-westerners&quot;&gt;Chinese Design for Westerners&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lu gave a fantastic talk on how typography and design is handled on the web in China. Think it&amp;#39;s enough to just translate the text? Think again. Different culture, technology, and aesthetics play a part in the design of websites in China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The average chinese font file contains 20,000+ characters! Weighs between 3–10MB, impossible for web embedding.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chinese characters can be really beautiful, emulating the calligraphy style. The presentation inspired me to play around with paint and canvas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-captioned data-instgrm-version=&quot;6&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/-cHL5EzSm4/&quot; style=&quot; color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;First go at Chinese writing turned out a bit crap as expected. It was nice to focus on one small thing though.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;A photo posted by Lewis Nyman (@lewisnyman) on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2015-11-23T19:34:59+00:00&quot;&gt;Nov 23, 2015 at 11:34am PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;script async defer src=&quot;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Matthew Young&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Designing Pelican Books&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matthew Young is a book cover designer working for Penguin. As a huge fan Penguin books I consumed this presentation with the wide eyes of a child. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matthew spoke about the design objectives and process behind the relaunch of Pelican Books. It was a great example a well designed modern business model for books with classic aesthetics. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Sarah Hyndman&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Think outside the font&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sarah runs &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.typetasting.com/&quot;&gt;Type Tasting,&lt;/a&gt; which investigates ways type influences our perception and decision making. If you&amp;#39;ve ever had a colleage or client ask you if a custom typeface is really worth the effort, I&amp;#39;d advise you to play one of Sarah&amp;#39;s games with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She&amp;#39;s invented some really fun, interactive ways of showing people the power of the right type. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OXc-VZ4Vwbo&quot;&gt;Watch her TED talk.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, I&amp;#39;ve so glad I went. I felt like I gave me a lot to think about be be excited about!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://lewisnyman.co.uk/blog/ampersand-2015/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://lewisnyman.co.uk/blog/ampersand-2015/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pre-ampersand Conf</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Whoops! Turns out you shouldn&amp;#39;t write a blog title “Writing Again”. That&amp;#39;s a bit of a jinx and it means you won&amp;#39;t write again for another three months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve had a good week this week. A fair amount of designing without development. More than I expected to do and more than I&amp;#39;ve done in a long time which is a nice surprise. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow is &lt;a href=&quot;http://2015.ampersandconf.com&quot;&gt;Ampersand Conf 2015.&lt;/a&gt; I had a good chat with some of the attendees over a burger and beers and I&amp;#39;m looking forward to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best keep it short and sweet. In case I use up my writing juices for another three months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chao!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://lewisnyman.co.uk/blog/pre-ampersand-conf/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://lewisnyman.co.uk/blog/pre-ampersand-conf/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thanks Hybrid</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s been a while since I&amp;#39;ve written here. The trip to Minneapolis in June threw my mojo off and once I lost my routine it became easy to not write.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Loads has happened in the past two months! I spoke at &lt;a href=&quot;http://drupalcampnorth.org/&quot;&gt;Drupal Camp North,&lt;/a&gt; I sprinted on Drupal 8 at &lt;a href=&quot;https://groups.drupal.org/node/474418&quot;&gt;Wunderkraut Munich.&lt;/a&gt; I just got back from Dublin where I attended the last excellent &lt;a href=&quot;hybridconf.net&quot;&gt;HybridConf.&lt;/a&gt; It was a common theme of conversation how much the conference would be missed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m going to miss Hybrid, like &lt;a href=&quot;http://2013.buildconf.com/&quot;&gt;Build,&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://newadventuresconf.com/&quot;&gt;New Adventures in Web Design&lt;/a&gt; before it. It feels like a friendly home, and it&amp;#39;s really hard to pull that off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope we find a way of producing this kind of conference without expecting someone to burn out or lose money year-on-year.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://lewisnyman.co.uk/blog/writing-again/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://lewisnyman.co.uk/blog/writing-again/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Moving from Github pages to self hosted Jekyll</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last year I &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/hello-jekyll/&quot;&gt;migrated this site to Jekyll.&lt;/a&gt; One of the reasons was I really didn&amp;#39;t want to worry about my own server, and the option was there to use Github pages for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a custom build process for my site, using Grunt. This meant I couldn&amp;#39;t take full advantage of the automated build process of Github pages. I built the site on my local machine and used &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/robwierzbowski/grunt-build-control&quot;&gt;grunt-build-control&lt;/a&gt; to deploy this to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lewisnyman/lewisnyman.github.io&quot;&gt;separate github repo.&lt;/a&gt; Not pretty but it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, I&amp;#39;ve been feeling the need to own my server again. It&amp;#39;s a pain having to build on my own machine, meaning I&amp;#39;m tied to it for creating content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I want to &lt;a href=&quot;(/blog/indie-web-camp-2015/)&quot;&gt;move towards publishing more content&lt;/a&gt; on this site I need to make it more flexible. I thought about introducing support for &lt;a href=&quot;http://indiewebcamp.com/note&quot;&gt;notes&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://indiewebcamp.com/micropub&quot;&gt;micropub&lt;/a&gt; and realised that having an automated build process was a blocker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also want to start pulling in all my data from other services I use and maybe doing something cool (eg. &lt;a href=&quot;https://gyrosco.pe&quot;&gt;gyrosco.pe&lt;/a&gt;) . To do that, I&amp;#39;m going to need a persistent server somewhere storing and serving data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was my process:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install Nginx and setup a folder that serves HTML from test.lewisnyman.co.uk (for now)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install build dependencies (RVM, NPM, Bundler, Sinatra, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a build script that runs a Sinatra server, nginx forwards all requests to api.lewisnyman.co.uk to there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setup the Github webhook to hit the api endpoint on push&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Debug the sinatra script for an hour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m happy to put the build script on github once it&amp;#39;s tested and I know it&amp;#39;s secure. It&amp;#39;s very similar to the one in the tutorial &lt;a href=&quot;http://petemichaud.github.io/2013/09/05/multisite-server-jekyll-digitalocean.html&quot;&gt;Automagic Multisite Server with Jekyll and Nginx on a DigitalOcean Droplet&lt;/a&gt; but with less abstraction to keep it simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used these tutorials and documentation to help me set up the Digital Ocean droplet and the build process. I want to write this up in more detail as simple tutorial for newbies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Special thanks to the lovely &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/joesb&quot;&gt;Joe Baker&lt;/a&gt; for giving me some pointers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-install-nginx-on-centos-7&quot;&gt;How To Install Nginx on CentOS 7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nginx.org/en/docs/beginners_guide.html&quot;&gt;Nginx beginners guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://petemichaud.github.io/2013/09/05/multisite-server-jekyll-digitalocean.html&quot;&gt;Automagic Multisite Server with Jekyll and Nginx on a DigitalOcean Droplet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-install-node-js-on-a-centos-7-server&quot;&gt;How To Install Node.js on a CentOS 7 server&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://rvm.io/rvm/install&quot;&gt;Installing RVM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sinatrarb.com/documentation.html&quot;&gt;Sinatra documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jonathanstark.com/blog/deploying-code-automatically-with-github-webhooks&quot;&gt;Deploying Automatically with Github WebHooks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.github.com/webhooks/&quot;&gt;Github webhooks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://lewisnyman.co.uk/blog/moving-from-github-pages-to-self-hosted-jekyll/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://lewisnyman.co.uk/blog/moving-from-github-pages-to-self-hosted-jekyll/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Indie Web Camp 2015</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last Saturday I attended my first &lt;a href=&quot;https://indiewebcamp.com/2015/Brighton&quot;&gt;Indie Web Camp.&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;#39;ve been using this site a lot more recently and I&amp;#39;ve been really excited to improve and add to it. I like the idea of owning my own data, but it&amp;#39;s always felt like a mammoth task to real in all the services I rely on. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I run my site on Jekyll, it felt like a big barrier to getting my data in and out of the static site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found a fellow ex-gowalla user in &lt;a href=&quot;https://adactio.com&quot;&gt;Jeremy&lt;/a&gt; and we briefly lamented the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.quora.com/Where-did-my-Gowalla-data-go&quot;&gt;lack of data export&lt;/a&gt; years after the &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.gowalla.com/&quot;&gt;Facebook acquisition.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned a lot about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://indiewebcamp.com/Principles&quot;&gt;principles of the Indie Web movement,&lt;/a&gt; and how to achieve this using &lt;a href=&quot;https://indiewebcamp.com/POSSE&quot;&gt;POSSE,&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://indiewebcamp.com/PESOS&quot;&gt;PESOS,&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://indiewebcamp.com/backfeed&quot;&gt;Backfeed.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also found out about &lt;a href=&quot;http://indiewebify.me/&quot;&gt;IndieWebify.Me,&lt;/a&gt; a step-by-step guide to owning your own data. This felt achievable! I no longer felt intimidated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I using the validation tools I realised my login links did work as expected. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lewisnyman/lewisnyman.co.uk-source/commit/b1c7bf17f6e278e35ccbfd79cd22c210073e10bd&quot;&gt;I added invisible links in the head of every page.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day we went for a drink and I introduced a few people to Burger Brothers. That&amp;#39;s always enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sunday was the hack day, which I missed because I was up in London hanging out with family. I did get a chance to work on my site a little, and luckily for me there were other attendees who were running Jekyll sites I could learn from as they were working through the same problems I was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://benjamin.parry.is/writing/testing-webmentions/&quot;&gt;Benjamin Parry&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://paulrobertlloyd.com/2015/07/webmentions&quot;&gt;Paul Robert Lloyd&lt;/a&gt; for working out in the open, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lewisnyman/lewisnyman.co.uk-source/issues/12&quot;&gt;enabling my own attempts at implementing Webmentions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I&amp;#39;ve done this correctly, they should receive a webmention on their site.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://lewisnyman.co.uk/blog/indie-web-camp-2015/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://lewisnyman.co.uk/blog/indie-web-camp-2015/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Shifting from conflict to learning</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve started reading &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/0670921343/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1634&amp;amp;creative=19450&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0670921343&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=lewisnymancou-21&amp;amp;linkId=62KFSUTSNRZHMVJP&quot;&gt;Difficult Conversations: How to Discuss What Matters Most.&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;#39;m a quarter of the way through andI already want to recommend this book to everyone I&amp;#39;ve ever met or will meet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One concept that applies situations of conflict is shifting &amp;#39;learning mode&amp;#39;. Bare in mind that both parties usually think they are the ones who are in the right. You put aside your perspective of right and wrong and dig deeper into the &amp;#39;why&amp;#39; of someones actions. Instead of making judgments on someones character, you find out why they acted like they did and how the situation looks from their perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Move from certainty to curiosity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of asking yourself “How can they think that?!” ask yourself, “I wonder what information they have that I don&amp;#39;t?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of asking “How can they be so irrational?” ask “How might they see the world in which their view makes sense?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you accept both perspectives, and remove the idea that only one can be the right and the other wrong, you accept the fact that two people can have different experiences and thoughts. You can move forward together instead of butting heads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next time I catch myself thinking “Who&amp;#39;s wrong or right here?” I&amp;#39;m going to make more effort to listen and accept both perspectives of the story.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://lewisnyman.co.uk/blog/shifting-from-conflict-to-learning/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://lewisnyman.co.uk/blog/shifting-from-conflict-to-learning/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Increase your chances of speaking at Drupalcon with an english session recording.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I was replying to a request for feedback for a rejected DrupalCon session submission in the frontend track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s a snippet of general advice for any speaker for whom english is a second language:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We couldn&amp;#39;t find any videos that demonstrated your english presentation skills. As DrupalCon is an english speaking conference, it&amp;#39;s really important that we can assess this. Picking a speaker without any video examples is very risky for a track chair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would definitely look for english speaking camps that are recording video to help your chances of speaking at DrupalCon in the future. Maybe if a camp asks you to speak you can ask them about recording the session on video as a bargaining chip? ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Camps that record their sessions are providing a valuable service to the community and to their speakers. We should encourage them by giving them better speakers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://lewisnyman.co.uk/blog/increase-your-chances-of-speaking-at-drupalcon-with-english-session-recording/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://lewisnyman.co.uk/blog/increase-your-chances-of-speaking-at-drupalcon-with-english-session-recording/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A week in Minneapolis</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s been nine days since I&amp;#39;ve written here. I can&amp;#39;t remember having a spare five minutes the whole week when I didn&amp;#39;t went to head straight to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a week! After flying in on Sunday, Ivan took me on a bicycle tour of Minneapolis to keep jet lag away. It was perfect weather and barely any traffic. The lakes just west of Minneapolis are glorious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;4&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/p/4P9hqETSll/&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;A photo posted by Lewis Nyman (@lewisnyman)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2015-06-22T23:11:19+00:00&quot;&gt;Jun 22, 2015 at 4:11pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monday was a nice, Bojhan and I settled in and visited the Mall of America, which has a pretty impressive Lego store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://photos-4.dropbox.com/t/2/AADm78YvKP-zgUBgYAEvHUXKZV_lmWniFcSMp-WcHwCt0g/12/1646407/jpeg/2048x1536/3/_/1/2/2015-06-22%2014.31.52.jpg/EPuCrAEYyuXtRCABKAE/3-HNJXQXn82tN3OFx_fqC3ScmukmgiC3vMcunqb-sUY&quot; alt=&quot;The lego shop roof&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also had a chance to walk along the Mississippi river and past the historic flour mills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;4&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/p/4gJ5_CzSsy/&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;A photo posted by Lewis Nyman (@lewisnyman)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2015-06-29T06:07:21+00:00&quot;&gt;Jun 28, 2015 at 11:07pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://photos-3.dropbox.com/t/2/AACWqFx5TmJeOQ-KtvHYYTMAHKwn85ygyOzH7_0OCgyfMw/12/1646407/jpeg/2048x1536/3/_/1/2/2015-06-22%2015.24.05.jpg/EPuCrAEYyuXtRCABKAE/G6RhTowFciNzv310AI4objSQiyMl0-IiwYOHWG-mAAY%2C-Bmjhq0MFaumWGcQG97FeMmezi1hAjW0VlyWPGvgDwQ&quot; alt=&quot;A view of the Mississippi river&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tuesday was the beginning of the usability study. It was a full day of observation and analysis. In the evening Ivan took us to watch a Minnesota Twins baseball game. It was exciting and really filling. Fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://photos-1.dropbox.com/t/2/AADgUqHDaSIisYNod4gfNxPFcUsEEK3LNSar9RbQPkqdFw/12/1646407/jpeg/2048x1536/3/_/1/2/2015-06-22%2019.29.59.jpg/EPuCrAEYyuXtRCABKAE/tw2-TuW45-85o4XAZCHaZQkjQ5V0tw_VHsDpGamot7g&quot; alt=&quot;Me, Bojhan, and Ivan at the baseball&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wednesday was another early start with another full day of observation. It was great to watch Nick and Joe from the University work and collaborate with everyone in the room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, we analysed and prioritised all the issues we found during the previous two days. 140 issues! This took a really long time...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friday, the camp started and everyone but me had presentations to give. I spent a good amount of time working on the Saturday presentation on the results of the usability study. I also watched Todds keynote again, and I loved it just as much as when I saw it in Bogota.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saturday, we had a presentation to give. We were tweaking the slides up until the session was due to start! I&amp;#39;m not very comfortable sharing the stage with others and I wasn&amp;#39;t used to using Google Drive to present. Even so it went surprisingly well! It was great to present alongside Angie, Bojhan, Ivan, Link, and Nick. I&amp;#39;m glad Nick made it to the camp, as he&amp;#39;s so full of energy and valuable advice. After the presentation we could finally relax a little :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sunday? Sprinting! Another early start. We spent the first hour or so finishing up the issues spreadsheet and then spent what little time we had discussing any tricky issues with people in the room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish I had time to write up each day separately but at least I dumped it out of my head before I land in Zürich and back to normal work life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script async defer src=&quot;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://lewisnyman.co.uk/blog/a-week-in-minneapolis/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://lewisnyman.co.uk/blog/a-week-in-minneapolis/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Flying to Minneapolis tomorrow</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow I&amp;#39;ll be catching a flight to Minneapolis, via Amsterdam. The total travel time is over ten hours, so I&amp;#39;m brainstorming something to be productive with on the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m eager to finish &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/B00HVPSXNS/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1634&amp;creative=19450&amp;creativeASIN=B00HVPSXNS&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=lewisnymancou-21&amp;linkId=NGNBPJH7E3TMR627&quot;&gt;One Hundred Years of Solitude&lt;/a&gt; or maybe start reading &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/0670921343/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1634&amp;creative=19450&amp;creativeASIN=0670921343&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=lewisnymancou-21&amp;linkId=62KFSUTSNRZHMVJP&quot;&gt;Difficult Conversations: How to Discuss What Matters Most.&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;#39;ve also been hacking around with Wunderkraut&amp;#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://hubot.github.com/&quot;&gt;hubot&lt;/a&gt; instance. We affectionately named him &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/WunderRoot/cato&quot;&gt;cato.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m also really looking forward to improving this site. Now that I&amp;#39;m using it more and more people are visiting it, it feels like a higher priority to me now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://lewisnyman.co.uk/blog/flying-to-minneapolis-tomorrow/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://lewisnyman.co.uk/blog/flying-to-minneapolis-tomorrow/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weight loss lessons</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I read an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.loopinsight.com/2015/06/18/follow-up-to-how-i-lost-over-40-pounds-using-healthkit-and-apple-watch/&quot;&gt;inspiring blog post&lt;/a&gt; by Jim Dalrymple, of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.loopinsight.com/&quot;&gt;The Loop.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He wrote about his weight loss of fourty pounds over ten months, which is pretty incredible. For someone who admitted he never though about fitness before now, he has a great attitude. Here are the lessons I&amp;#39;ve learnt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Become aware of everything you eat&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you understand what your putting in your mouth, you become so much more aware of the decisions you make. Myfitnesspal does a great job at this, not just telling you your calories, but your sodium, protein, carbohydrates, and more. You quickly realise that some foods that are &amp;#39;healthy&amp;#39; really aren&amp;#39;t. That salad would be healthy... if it wasn&amp;#39;t covered in french dressing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Don&amp;#39;t become obsessed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using MyFitnessPal is an approximation of the food I’m eating every day. I don’t count the number of strawberries I eat, I just say, “Yeah, that’s about a quarter of a cup.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;One day at a time&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I looked at each day in tenths of pounds. If I was down by even one-tenth, that was great for me. If I was up, I looked at what I did the day before that may of caused it. I didn’t feel guilty or beat myself, I just tried to do better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Good days and bad days&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All I wanted to do is try. Every single day. I’ll have some good days and some bad days, but I didn’t care, I’d just try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://lewisnyman.co.uk/blog/weight-loss-lessons/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://lewisnyman.co.uk/blog/weight-loss-lessons/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
